Guide to the Frank Dailey papers, 1937-1944 UA.29.02.0240
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Frank Dailey papers
1937-1944
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Dailey, Frank Walter.
Duke University. University Archives
UA.29.02.0240
0.5 Linear Feet
The collection largely includes photographs taken by Dailey while a student at Duke University. They date from 1938-1940 and include various subjects, including football and the social activities of students. There is a small cache of clippings/newsprint and ephemera.
Provenance
The Frank Dailey Papers were received by the Duke University Archives as a gift in February 2014.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Historical note
Frank Walter Dailey was born November 7, 1919 in Buffalo, NY. He received his A. B. degree from Duke in 1941 and his doctorate of Juris Prudence from Duke in 1948. Between his degrees, Dailey served in the United States Navy during World War II. While at Duke, he played trumpet in the Duke Band and was a photographer for the Duke 'n' Duchess, the school's first student-supported humor magazine. He passed away on March 21, 2012.
Collection Overview
The collection contains largely photographs taken by Dailey during his time as a student at Duke. The topics of his photographs range from football to dances to fraternity initiations. There are four photograph albums, described in greater detail below, as well s loose photographs which have been sleeved. Many of the loose photographs are enlarged copies of images found in the albums. There are also some clippings and newsprint which may contain published photographs taken by Dailey and ephemera. The collection ranges in date from 1937-1944.
Dailey, Frank Walter.; Duke University--Athletics; Duke University--Students--Societies, etc; Duke University--Students--Social life and customs; Duke University. University Archives
- Frank Dailey papers, 1937-1944
  - Photographs, 1940, 5 folders (Box 1, Folder 1-5)
    Scope and Contents
    Subjects include women students, the Nereidian Club, football, an unidentified plane crash, Goon Day, Beta Omega Sigma initiation, and social activities of students.
  - Photograph Album #1, 1937, 1938-1939, 1 folders (Box 1, Folder 6)
    The subject of this album is Duke football, both the 1938 and 1939 seasons. There are images of floats from the 1938 Homecoming parade (Duke vs. Georgia Tech), the Homecoming game featuring 3 prizewinning merchants' floats, halftime and before the start of the game. There are also images of displays and signs on campus in preparation for the Duke-Georgia Tech game as well as the games against North Carolina State and Pittsburgh. Additionally, there are images of the Duke Band, UNC Band, football players, signs created before the first home game against Colgate in 1939. Additional subjects include Homecoming 1939 (bonfire, signs, parade, floats), UNC game 1939 (bonfire, signs, freshman sponsor, mascots) and final game with North Carolina State.
  - Photograph Album #2, 1938-1939, 1 folders (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Subjects of this album include the following: Duke Chapel, fire at Peanut Cafe, Dunkirk Lighthouse, Ellis-Stone window display celebrating Robert E. Lee's birthday, Duke Centennial, Duke vs. Philadelphia Athletics (baseball), Durham tobacco auction, Duke Union kitchen, Tommy Dorsey, student life/social activities/co-eds, Beta Omega Sigma initiation, dances, May Queen, New York World's Fair/Bronx Zoo/Times Square, Duke carnival, Duke Gardens, mascots, Tombs annual initiation, football, Duke Band, Durham nightlife, and Goon Day. Goon Day is described in the album as such: one day each year, the sophomore women force the freshmen women to dress in ridiculous costumes and then proceed to humiliate them until 8pm. After this time, the freshmen are allowed to do what they want to the sophomores they are able to catch. Of particular note is an example of Dailey's talent for trick photography, featuring an image he created of the Washington Duke statue standing up.
  - Photograph Album #3, 1940, 1 folders (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Album includes candid shots of co-eds, Beta Omega Sigma initiation, and female students playing tennis and sunbathing.
  - Photograph Album #4, 1940, 1 folders (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Subjects associated with this album include dances, candid shots of students, Washington, DC trip, Artie Shaw's band, students playing in the snow, student couples, Nereidian club, Sigma Kappa pledge dance and sorority room, Cotton Pickers Ball, a female student on Washington Duke statue, track meet, Goon Day, and dorm room interior.
  - "Go West Young Men," by Bud Coolican, 1939, 1 folders (Box 1, Folder 10)
    From Syracuse paper after Duke-Syracuse game
  - Dope Sheet: Duke-Colgate game, 1938 Oct. 8; Duke-Georgia Tech game (Homecoming), 1938, 1 folders (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Publications: "Two Bells," 1937 Oct. 11; "A Brief Guide to the Chapel," 1937 June, 1 folders (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Tickets to the Duke-Colgate game, 1938 Oct. 8 and Duke-Pittsburgh game, 1939 Oct. 14; V-Mail, 1944 Nov. 15, 1 folders (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Class if 1941 Golden Anniversary Chanticleer, 1991, 1 folders (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, 1938, undated, 1 folders (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Collegiate Digest, volume VII, issue 9; volume IX, issue 13, 1 folders (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Durham Morning Herald's Duke Football Homecoming Addition (supplement only), 1939 Oct. 21, 1940 Nov. 2, 1 folders (Oversize-folder 1)